majorgeeks.com 2019-05-28

# Privacy - MajorGeeks

MajorGeeks.Com always respects our reader's rights to privacy.

MajorGeeks.Com rarely collects any data on anyone. Frankly the next 1000 or so words you are about to read can be summed up with we use ads and they do collected data. Occasionally we collect information about our readers through polls or contest and giveaway registrations. The data collected may be used to determine the demographic information about the entire MajorGeeks.Com audience and/or to help target advertising. Majorgeeks.com does set cookies. Cookies are small text files that store information in your web browser. This information may include your site preferences, session identification, HTTP information, and IP address. You can set your browser to not receive cookies, but this may limit your ability to browse MajorGeeks and it's subdomains. MajorGeeks does not store this cookie. It is on your machine. MajorGeeks.Com does not sell, rent, lease or allow any third parties to view or use the information collected unless the reader consents through the registration process. 

MajorGeeks does maintain a message forum. The software we use is Xenforo. The data collected is used for to log in and use the system and read, wrote, or reply to messages. Cookies are collected and used so that the system can remember things about you. Like what thread you have read or your personal options. The data that needs to be stored on the system is encrypted by the messaging software. IP addresses of computers used to visit MajorGeeks Forum are logged. This includes when first registering for an account, managing your account details, writing a private or public message or performing any other transaction which results in data being transferred to or from your computer and the website in question. Your IP address is not visible to the public at any time.

Your rights:  
You have the right to receive free information about your stored personal data, the correction and limitation of processing at any time within the scope of the applicable legal provisions. Please note that we require proof of your identity for such requests, for data security reasons.

Information:  
If you have an active user account on this website, you can log in to our user management tool with your login to get an overview of all your stored personal data.

Data portability:  
You have the right to obtain the personally identifiable information we have stored based on your consent in a structured, common, machine-readable format. If you have an active user account on this site, log in to our user management tool and select "Download this information". <https://forums.majorgeeks.com/gdpr/index.php>

Deletion and objection:  
You can always delete your active user account. This will delete all personal data stored in your user account in accordance with Art. 17 (1)  
(b) GDPR. To delete your active user account, log in to our user management tool ( <https://forums.majorgeeks.com/gdpr/index.php)> with your login and select the option "Delete my account". Please note that this process is not reversible.

Any public postings that you have written will be anonymized in this case, since otherwise existing topics will be taken out of context.  
Moreover, this would contradict freedom of expression and freedom of information.

MajorGeeks uses the Disqus Comment Platform to manage comments on the site and subsites. All data in that regard is maintained by Disqus. This is their **[privacy policy](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy)** and account information. 

MajorGeeks.Com does maintain a mailing list that is used to keep 

_subscribers_

informed about certain deals, promotions, updates or events. The mailing list is double opt-in and can be subscribed to at any time. The Mailing list is maintained by Mail Chimp and their **[privacy policy is here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)**.

MajorGeeks.Com uses third-party advertisers to serve ads and collect information when you visit MajorGeeks.Com. When online advertisements are displayed to you, one or more cookies may be placed on your computer. Some of these companies may use information (not including personally identifiable information such as your name or email address) about your visits to MajorGeeks.Com and other sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Our ads are served by OpenX Adserver that manages the cookies, counting and display of the advertisements. 

Google Adsense:  
Our website uses Google Adsense as advertising service provider. Google maintains a Privacy Shield certification, thereby guaranteeing a level of data protection adapted to the European Union.  
The operator is Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. You can find the privacy policy of Google at:  
<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

Please note that we opt out of personalized ads in countries of the European Economic Area (EEA). If you are living in a non-EEA country you may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting the aboutads.info website.

* * *

MajorGeeks Top Advertising Partners: (for your convenience)

[Google](https://www.google.com/) \- Their [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/privacy.html) and [opt-out](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/view)  
[Sovrn](https://www.sovrn.com/) \- Their [Privacy Policy](https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/) and [opt-out](https://info.evidon.com/pub_info/2672?v=1&nt=0&nw=false)  
[Openads](https://www.openx.com/legal/privacy-policy/) \- Their [Privacy Policy](https://www.openx.com/legal/privacy-policy/) and [opt-out](https://www.openx.com/legal/interest-based-advertising/)  
[Exponential](https://exponential.com/) \- Their [Privacy Policy](https://exponential.com/privacy/) and [opt-out](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/)

Affilate Sales

[Avangate](https://www.avangate.com/privacy.php) \- Their [Privacy Policy](https://www.cleverbridge.com/?scope=contact&id=evhd7ETHEs&progress=privacyp)  
[CleverBridge](https://www.cleverbridge.com/) \- Their [Privacy Policy](https://www.cleverbridge.com/?scope=contact&id=evhd7ETHEs&progress=privacyp)

MajorGeeks.com does use other advertising networks and third-party networks, whose privacy policies will always be listed on their respective sites. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on our site, other websites and other forms of media about goods and services of interest to you. Many of these companies belong to the [Network Advertising Initiative](https://www.networkadvertising.org/). They offer a page where you can select which companies you wish to opt-out of behavioral advertising methods for its members. You can find that here.[https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp#).

MajorGeeks.com uses Google Analytics. Google Analytics is software that compiles s data about our visitors. It acts like web server logs, only in a better format with additional information. Google Analytics tracks things like what site you came from, how long you stayed on the website, what country people are from, what pages were viewed and what computer or browser you are using… and much more. However, no personally identifiable data is collected in this way. The data collected helps us understand who our audience is as well as convey the statistics for help sell advertising on the website. You can opt out of Google tracking cookie here <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads> or you can also use their browser plugin. <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

We also, like well everyone use Youtube to post our videos. You can read the Youtube privacy policy here. <https://www.youtube.com/static?template=privacy_guidelines>

MajorGeeks.Com takes all reasonable measures to keep the information disclosed secure. However, MajorGeeks.Com assumes no responsibility for any breach of security to this data.

Responsible for this website is:

Major Geeks  
7 Braniff Drive  
Camillus, NY 13031  
USA

E-Mail: jim@majorgeeks.com

Now drop and give us 10100.
